Dattatraya Walunj

Data Analyst(Data Scientist)

Shitole Nagar, Old Sangvi Pune, 411027 9763529046 drwalunj.2010@gmail.com

SUMMARY

1 year of experience in Python(Django) and 6 months of experience in Data Analyst(Data Science). Quick learning abilities to adapt to current technology and market needs. Experience in machine learning problem solving during projects in Internships. Experience in data science libraries like NumPy and Pandas with thorough knowledge of python visualization in Seaborn, Plotly, Matplotlib, Keras, Tensorflow and Tableau.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Python, Beginner level C, C++, Java, PHP, SQL.

Frontend Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Backend Technologies: Django, Flask (Python)

Operating Systems: Linux, Windows

Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite, MongoDB

Others: Git, Bitbucket, Sourcetree, Postman (API

development), spaCy, Scikit-Learn, SciPy, Natural Language Processing (NLP) and Deep Learning.

EXPERIENCE

RapidAl Technologies, Pune - Data Analyst (Data Scientist)

SEP 2019 - MAR 2020

- **Resume Parsers:** A simple resume parser used for extracting information from resumes.
- The main challenge is to extract names from resumes. I used a more sophisticated tool called spaCy. spaCy comes with Pre-trained models for tagging, parsing and entity recognition.

- To extract phone and email from a resume used a regular expression model (re.findall). To extract skills from a resume used Sentence Tokenization and Word Tokenization Technique.
- For extracting Education Details from resumes use the NLTK module.

Brainfuse, New York - Online Tutor/Expert

SEP 2017 - PRESENT

- Assessing the difficulty that the student is having with the work.
- Designing/finding a way to guide the student and implementing it.
- Communicating throughout the session.

Techknit IT Enabled Services Pvt. Ltd, Pune - Online Tutor/Expert

AUG 2013 - SEP 2017

- Clarifying the Student's Needs.
- Choosing an Effective Approach.
- Ensuring Student Understanding.
- The experience of understanding another person's condition from their perspective.

PROJECT

Resume Formatting:

Parsing experience related details from the resume and rewrite it with defined destination formatting.

- Parsed .doc, .docx, and .pdf file formats.
- Project done using python.
- Here the thing that is captured from each company given in the resume. I captured the Job title, Name of the company, City, State, Start date and End date.

Credit Risk Analysis - Loan Default Prediction

OBJECTIVE:

- Create a predictive model to classify each borrower as a defaulter or not using the data collected when the loan has been given.
- Minimize the risk of borrowers defaulting on loans using a created model.

PROBLEM STATEMENT:

 To classify if the borrower will default the loan using borrower's finance history. That means, given a set of new predictor variables, we need to predict the target variable as 1 => Defaulter and 0 => Non-Defaulter.

EVALUATION APPROACH:

- I used a classification algorithm for solving our problem. It establishes a relation between input features and output features.
- For the Loan default prediction project, False Negatives Rate is the best metric to evaluate the model. Lower the number of false negatives, better the model is.
- From the confusion matrices, I infer that the Logistic Regression model had the least False Negative Rate (FNR).

EDUCATION

Department of Mathematics, University of Pune - M. Tech

JUNE 2010 - JULY 2013

Modern College, Pune(Shivajinagar) - B.Sc(Mathematics)

JUNE 2009- JUNE 2010

MY WEBSITES

https://www.pdgmpx.com

https://airesumeparser.herokuapp.com

https://github.com/Dattatraya77/Corona-Patient-Prediction